<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on The RDK</title>
    <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/</link>
    <description>The RDK (Books)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 11:24:29 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://the-rdk.github.io/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Prince by Niccolo Machiavelli</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/the_prince/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 11:51:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/the_prince/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/the_prince.epub&#34;&gt;Link to epub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/the_prince.pdf&#34;&gt;Link to PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club: Don Quixote by Miguel de Cervantes</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/don_quixote/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 10:24:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/don_quixote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/don_quixote.pdf&#34;&gt;Link to PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/don_quixote.epub&#34;&gt;Link to epub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club: Hegemony How-To by Jonathon Smucker</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/hegemony_how_to/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 18:22:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/hegemony_how_to/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/hegemony_how_to.pdf&#34;&gt;Link to PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/hegemony_how_to.epub&#34;&gt;Link to epub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club: Propaganda by Edward Bernays</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/propaganda/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 09:26:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/propaganda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/propaganda.pdf&#34;&gt;Link to PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/propaganda.epub&#34;&gt;Link to epub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conscious and intelligent manipulation of the organized habits and opinions of the masses is an important element in democratic society. Those who manipulate this unseen mechanism of society constitute an invisible government which is the true ruling power of our country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The voice of the people expresses the mind of the people, and that mind is made up for it by the group leaders in whom it believes and by those persons who understand the manipulation of public opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edward Bernays is the tribal father of Public Relations, best known for selling cigarettes to feminists. &lt;em&gt;Propaganda&lt;/em&gt; is a polemic for the role of propaganda in civil society and a sales pitch for his services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bernays takes a page from Pareto in modelling society as divided between a decision-making elite and those under their influence. This natural divide presents itself across various domains, from fashion to politics. Propaganda, he argues, is a critical tool in the arsenal of leadership and an essential aspect of organising civil society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They not only appealed to the individual by means of every approach—visual, graphic, and auditory—to support the national endeavor, but they also secured the cooperation of the key men in every group—persons whose mere word carried authority to hundreds or thousands or hundreds of thousands of followers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are invisible rulers who control the destinies of millions. It is not generally realized to what extent the words and actions of our most influential public men are dictated by shrewd persons operating behind the scenes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was found too that four groups might help to change hat fashions: the society leader, the style expert, the fashion editor and writer, the artist who might give artistic approval to the styles, and beautiful mannequins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By identifying where his client&amp;rsquo;s interests intersect with the relevant group-think leader, Bernays produces a propaganda campaign. This campaign must coordinate its impact from multiple angles; Bernays describes this as an application of the psychological sciences (science by its older meaning - a field of knowledge). A pattern to his technique emerges: identify the authority figures, what makes it appealing and how human emotional life can be tied in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of familiar psychological motives were set in motion in the carrying out of this campaign. The aesthetic, the competitive, the gregarious, the snobbish (the impulse to follow the example of a recognized leader), the exhibitionist, and—last but by no means least—the maternal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book sells the role of Public Relations throughout its pages. The book proposed it as a solution to the race-to-the-bottom style of margin-cutting competition. Where consumers would benefit from lowered prices, companies can instead compete to sell an image by employing sophisticated advertising campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While advertising the field, Bernays uses both the carrot and the stick. He warns businesses of the dangers of the public&amp;rsquo;s mood swings. Without a well-paid consultant directing a company&amp;rsquo;s reputation, they may find themselves at the mob&amp;rsquo;s whims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If today big business were to seek to throttle the public, a new reaction similar to that of twenty years ago would take place and the public would rise and try to throttle big business with restrictive laws. Business is conscious of the public’s conscience. This consciousness has led to a healthy cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it is my conviction that as big business becomes bigger the need for expert manipulation of its innumerable contacts with the public will become greater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that competition in the future will not be only an advertising competition between individual products or between big associations, but that it will in addition be a competition of propaganda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bernay&amp;rsquo;s foretold propaganda-based competition shares a possible explanation for the state of corporate media today. The internet saw a relative calm before the onset of mass advertising, which would sanitise social media to maximise corporate image. Just as social media became increasingly artificial, the advertised moral and ideological positions have taken on increasing extremes. Could this attempt to compete by morally out-doing one another be the topsoil in which Woke Capital has grown?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our author, famous for associating cigarettes with the women&amp;rsquo;s suffrage movement, has some interesting observations regarding how women have organised politically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Women organised themselves and projected political power through their various clubs. Women built these clubs around hobbies or activities. The particular niche doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem of importance. What would begin as a club pushing for funding or policies directly relevant to their pursuit would soon become a mechanism for women to express power and influence society. After breaking through the societal inertia, they would entirely reshape society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the General Federation of Women’s Clubs, there are 13,000 clubs. Broadly classified, they include civic and city clubs, mothers’ and homemakers’ clubs, cultural clubs devoted to art, music or literature, business and professional women’s clubs, and general women’s clubs, which may embrace either civic or community phases, or combine some of the other activities listed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More important, it constitutes an organized channel through which women can make themselves felt as a definite part of public opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The great enemy of any attempt to change men’s habits is inertia. Civilization is limited by inertia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the women&amp;rsquo;s clubs were not explicitly political, they came to wield significant political power. The many disenfranchised young men of today should take note of this as building similar groups is the first step towards re-asserting their societal position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Films are named the latest and greatest in propaganda technology, and the same rings true today. Through YouTube, Odysee and Twitch, the video format has only gained popularity. Video games are also a novelty and have had a sizeable impact, particularly on today&amp;rsquo;s young men. However, its impact is particularly limited to this demographic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dissident Right literature revival has brought fresh ideas and energy to an otherwise deeply stagnated landscape, even if still firmly within the underground. I hope to see this energy spread and similarly re-invigorate film and gaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I were in his place I should have taken some of my brightest young men and set them to work for Broadway theatrical productions or apprenticed them as assistants to professional propagandists before recruiting them to the service of the party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The American motion picture is the greatest unconscious carrier of propaganda in the world today. It is a great distributor for ideas and opinions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Propaganda ends on a solid (perhaps even based, if I dare say) piece of advice and an appeal to the unavoidable reality of propaganda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you are not capable of managing your own wife,” was the reply, “the people will certainly believe that you are not capable of managing their money.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Propaganda will never die out. Intelligent men must realize that propaganda is the modern instrument by which they can fight for productive ends and help to bring order out of chaos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having finished the book, I&amp;rsquo;m left reflecting on the role of propaganda in leadership. Society has fallen under the sway of the mentally ill, who enjoy active promotion across all major forms of media. Is our current situation a failure to maintain a positive vision reinforced by effective propaganda for ordinary people?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club: On the Genealogy of Morals by Nietzsche</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/on_the_genealogy_of_morals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 22:29:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/on_the_genealogy_of_morals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/genealogy_of_morals.pdf&#34;&gt;Link to PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club: Father Giles of Ham by J.R.R. Tolkien</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/father_giles_of_ham/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 22:12:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/father_giles_of_ham/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/father_giles_of_ham.pdf&#34;&gt;Link to PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/father_giles_of_ham.epub&#34;&gt;Link to epub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club: The Camp of the Saints by Jean Raspail</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/camp_of_the_saints/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 09:36:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/camp_of_the_saints/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/camp_of_the_saints.pdf&#34;&gt;Link to PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/camp_of_the_saints.epub&#34;&gt;Link to epub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club: The Captive Mind by Czesław Miłosz</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/the_captive_mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 17:14:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/the_captive_mind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/the_captive_mind.pdf&#34;&gt;Link to PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/the_captive_mind.epub&#34;&gt;Link to epub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Captive Mind is a reflection of life in Poland under Soviet control. It explores the author&amp;rsquo;s confrontation with dialectic materialism and that of his fellow Authors. The observations and lessons learnt ring hauntingly relevant to our modern days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was only toward the middle of the twentieth century that the inhabitants of many European countries came, in general unpleasantly, to the realization that their fate could be inﬂuenced directly by intricate and abstruse books of philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well connected to the Polish Intelligentista, the book details how the more prominent members are manoeuvred into communist forms of thinking. Dialectic Materialism highlights how man is shaped by social forces, and as such the soviet regime seeks to take the reigns of cultural production as a means of population control. To achieve this goal it moves slowly and seduces with whispers, it presents The Method as the only scientific way in which to perceive and accurately depict reality. It provides rewards and encouraging words while gently increasing the pressure to conform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paradoxical as it may seem, it is this subjective impotence that convinces the intellectual that the one Method is right. Everything proves it is right. Dialectics: I predict the house will burn; then I pour gasoline over the stove. The house burns; my prediction is fulfilled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These artists&amp;rsquo; congresses reveal the inequality between the weapons of the dialectician and those of his adversary. A match between the two is like a duel between a foot soldier and a tank. Not that every dialectician is so very intelligent or so very well educated, but all his statements are enriched by the cumulated thought of the masters and their commentators. If every sentence he speaks is compact and eﬀective, that is not due to his own merits, but to those of the classics he has studied&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asking himself why he cannot escape from its embrace (even if he should want to), the intellectual replies that the measure of the Method&amp;rsquo;s accuracy lies in the strength of those who rule in its name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everyone can be convinced, yet Soviet society with its firm grip on social and legal institutions is a dangerous place for an infidel. A practice from Islamic countries where non-conformity faces a more upfront reprisal is adopted, Ketman. The practice of pretending to believe to avoid the wrath of the faithful and the strength of those who rule over the faithful. An adaptation (read: cope) from being made to hide one&amp;rsquo;s knowledge of the truth, the act of hiding it is artistically portrayed as a pleasurable habit. More believably, it is argued to heighten a man&amp;rsquo;s cunning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The people of the Mussulman East believe that &amp;ldquo;He who is in possession of truth must not expose his person, his relatives or his reputation to the blindness, the folly, the perversity of those whom it has pleased God to place and maintain in error.&amp;rdquo; One must, therefore, keep silent about one&amp;rsquo;s true convictions if possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The necessities which drive men to Ketman sharpen the intellect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most interesting aspect of the book lies in the Soviets preferred methods of control. Not content to just have writers under their thumb, control is implemented across all layers of society. Society itself is engineered to permit further methods for control. Collective farms, pitched as owning the means of production, function more importantly as a decentralised Panopticon. A humourous removal of workers&amp;rsquo; rights, the worker is not allowed to strike as they are the owners of the factory. Denying a worker&amp;rsquo;s family access to education should they not agree to police other workers. Solving unemployment by creating an endless number of bureaucratic jobs in their factories, drastically increasing the prices of basic goods. The care to separate potential leaders from the workers. The Soviet Union was an experiment in mass social engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because Communism recognizes that rule over men&amp;rsquo;s minds is the key to rule over an entire country, the word is the cornerstone of this system. Gamma became one of the chief press organizers in the city of Lublin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A peasant hut is the ideal place for partisans to eat, sleep, and work out plans of action. Therefore, a collective farm, where a man&amp;rsquo;s every step is easy to trace, guarantees a degree of control that is indispensable if one wants to preclude hostile underground activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Workers are told that a strike is a crime. Against whom are they to strike? Against themselves? After all, the means of production belong to them, the state belongs to them. But such an explanation is not very convincing. The workers, who dare not state aloud what they want, know that the goals of the state are far from identical with their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even the spiritual was machined into a regime tool; Christianity had given them plenty to work with. Coinciding with man&amp;rsquo;s portrayal as nothing more than a member of a social group, guilt is similarly collectivised into historical guilt. This weaponised guilt. Guilt as a means of control. Guilt not for what you have done, but what your social group can be historically blamed for. Does this ring a bell?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The specific trick of the Christian Stalinists is to lump these two concepts of guilt, individual and historical, together, while it is only in a few instances that these concepts coincide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the West a man subconsciously regards society as unrelated to him. Society indicates the limits he must not exceed; in exchange for this he receives a guarantee that no one will meddle excessively in his affairs. If he loses it&amp;rsquo;s his own fault; (&amp;hellip;) In the East there is no boundary between man and society. His game, and whether he loses or wins, is a public matter. He is never alone. If he loses it is not because of indifference on the part of his environment, but because his environment keeps him under such minute scrutiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communism is openly Globalist - &amp;ldquo;Workers of the World Unite&amp;rdquo;. Their approach is not so different from what we see today. The forced mixing of people, the forced opening of borders, the forced dissolution of national identity. The erasure of individual identity, of national identity, dressed in the attire of a Utopian fantasy. A necessity for their one-world government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of all these moves is to inter-mix the population of the Union. Only by dissolving individual nationalities in the &amp;ldquo;Russian sea&amp;rdquo; can one attain the goal of a single culture and a single universal language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One must always keep in mind the eventual goal, which is the melting down of all nations into a single mass. To this end, nationalism must be exterminated. Nationalism rests on the conviction that national culture is the expression of &amp;ldquo;national content in national form&amp;rdquo;; whereas, everybody knows that the content of national cultures has had until now a class character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Captive Mind is an excellent read, with lessons applicable to our modern day. It is an entry-level redpill in that it is normie appropriate, but it is also an effective redpill into the realities of Communism. While the book offers no counter-measures or forms of effective resistance, it does detail the methods and tricks used by the authoritarian Soviet regime. The book goes well with The Power of the Powerless by Václav Havel, a look into life under communism in the Czech Republic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet the letter I one day held in my hand was painful. It came from a family deported to Siberia from one of the Baltic states in March 1949, and was addressed to relatives in Poland. The family consisted of a mother and two daughters. Their letter was a terse account of their work on a kolkhoz. The last letters of every line were slightly stressed, and reading vertically one made out the words &amp;ldquo;Eternal Slave.&amp;rdquo; If such a letter happened to fall into my hands, then how many other, similarly disguised expressions of despair must have found their way to people who could not make any use of them. And, calculating the possibilities, how many such letters remained unwritten; how many of those who might have written them died of hunger and overwork, repeating those hopeless words, &amp;ldquo;Eternal Slave&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club: 88 Precepts by David Lane</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/88_precepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 22:16:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/88_precepts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/88_precepts.pdf&#34;&gt;Link to PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/88_precepts.epub&#34;&gt;Link to epub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;88 Precepts is a short collection of Neo-Nazi philosophical maxims and is best known for introducing the infamous 1488 slogan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must secure the existence of our people and a future for white children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14 Words, 88 Precepts, HH. With its core ideals thoroughly embedded within the far-right, its target demographic will already be familiar with its best ideas. Your time on 4chan will have already filled you in on the best it has to offer. What is left still has some punch but suffers from familiarity and the occasional sophistry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One measure of a man is cheerfulness in adversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Materialism leads men to seek artificial status through wealth or property. True social status comes from service to Family, Race and Nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Published in the early 1990s, 88 Precepts pre-dates the mainstream adoption of the internet. The author was David Lane, a former member of The John Birch Society, The Ku Klux Klan, The Aryan Nations and, most famously, The Order. Lane is documented as having stolen $4.1 million in car hijackings, organised military training and killed three people. He passed away in prison in 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truth does not fear investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of “equality” is declared a lie by every evidence of Nature. It is a search for the lowest common denominator, and its pursuit will destroy every superior race, nation, or culture. In order for a plow horse to run as fast as a race horse you would first have to cripple the race horse; conversely, in order for a race horse to pull as much as a plow horse, you would first have to cripple the plow horse. In either case, the pursuit of equality is the destruction of excellence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite suffering from how common its core ideas have become, 88 Precepts still has value to offer beyond its infamous 14 words. As a short read, it will have the most value to the more fresh-faced fellow traveller than the seasoned frog.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club: Always the Horizon by Murdoch Murdoch</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/always_the_horizon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 19:40:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/always_the_horizon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/always_the_horizon.pdf&#34;&gt;Link to PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Always The Horizon&amp;rsquo; by Murdoch Murdoch is the pseudonymous screenwriter&amp;rsquo;s first foray into a work of a more formal nature. While this fact may often be apparent in the text, with some staccato action sequences reading more like directions for an animator as opposed to a novella, Murdoch is effective in expressing the same hopeful ideals he portrays in his web animations in this new prosaic form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking cues from Nietzsche&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Thus Spake Zarathustra&amp;rsquo;, Greek mythology, gothic horror and fantasy stories, Murdoch encourages readers to fight against nihilism and despair. Instead, finding joy in imagining Sisyphus happy: striving to be the best person you can be, finding meaning in overcoming the challenges you face, and eternally running towards the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Murdoch rejects the cold, analytical fatalism endemic in modern society in favour of a romantic, perhaps even foolish, idealism. This is reflected even in the name of the protagonist, as the story is framed as a dialogue between The Sacred Clown and his faithful horse-riding companion, surrogates respectively for Murdoch and the reader himself, as they embark on a classic hero&amp;rsquo;s journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the tale, Murdoch also touches on a variety of issues the modern world faces: the futility of captured &amp;ldquo;democratic&amp;rdquo; systems, relations between the sexes, the failures of modern religion, death, and the parasitic forces of dissolution who prioritise their own selfish greed over higher ideals. The second-person narration draws the reader into the text as if Murdoch is speaking to us directly, and sections of text preceded with a dramatic &amp;ldquo;Know this:&amp;rdquo; serve to drive home the points Murdoch is attempting to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crux of Always The Horizon is a message of hope - that we might meet the world on its own terms with the same knowing glint in our eye as one might find in the eye of a Hindu guru. A knowledge that transcends nihilism and declares &amp;ldquo;nothing matters - so what!&amp;rdquo; - that the journey itself is enough to fulfil a man. And in that, at least, Murdoch echoes philosophers and priests throughout the ages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;quotes&#34;&gt;Quotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why have you come here, rider, to the grave of your fatherland? Have
you come to follow me? Know that I lead no man, but if you wish to
become my companion then I must make a single request of you. If
we are to take up this task and travel the all-too-arduous path, then
you must promise me that your eyes will remain transfixed, always,
on the horizon. There we will chase the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gnash my teeth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seventeen hundred years ago Constantine, curse his
name, undid all of the steps undertaken by Diocletian to hold on
to the memetic keys that the Romans had venerated since their
inception. Did these so-called “Romans” not realize that every step
further from mos maiorum was a step towards losing themselves?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let it be said that the new man will not
die for his own immortality, but rather will live for the continuation
of Being’s drive towards knowing – so that he may rest satisfied
on his death bed, secure in the knowledge that he took up the task
to aid truth’s pursuit of truth. Being to being. And that he like the
romantics who came before, and those who shall come after, chased
the sun with reckless abandon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know this, rider, hate is born from the womb of love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we make our escape we move to find higher ground, out towards
the mountain peaks. There we witness the metropolis in twilight,
finally submerged in the wave of the Nothing, completely lost to
time. Not even the grass that circled the walls of the city remains.
The landscape now resembles an alien world, devoid of life. The
insects and birds, men and women, the old and young, even the
streets and towers have been completely erased. But there, where
the lone soldier stood, lies a mound of debris – a small fragment of
the city wall, and the few moths that hover above, are now all that
remain of that once great city of light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man is a wolf to man. Great acts of unkindness run deep in all of our histories – or have you
forgotten the corpses that run alongside your Great Wall? You are
not my enemy, Liu Bei. You are only another aspect of Being. We are
both capable of the knowing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pub remains silent and I shout once more, “We shall ride under
lightning! For that was the weapon of Zeus and Jupiter and Taranis;
of Thor and Indra; of Perun, Perk  ̄unas, and Perkwunos! Let us become
wild men again! For you who dwell here, did I not ride alongside
you for years? Come with me again, let us ride out into the horizon!
Let us chase Sul, Helios, Arinna, Hvare-khshaeta, Surya and Sol
Invictus!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club: How to Win Friends and Influence People by Dale Carnegie</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/how_to_win_friends_and_influence_people/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 19:25:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/how_to_win_friends_and_influence_people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/how_to_win_friends_and_influence_people.pdf&#34;&gt;Link to PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/how_to_win_friends_and_influence_people.epub&#34;&gt;Link to epub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How to Win Friends And Influence People&amp;rdquo; by Dale Carnegie is a one-stop-shop for aspiring used car salesmen and middle managers to attain mastery in the laudable art of brown-nosing. The reader may at first consider the rules and principles laid out in this book rather simple, but as with Newton&amp;rsquo;s laws of motion and Pythagoras&amp;rsquo; theorem, Carnegie was the first to write them down. It is hardly a surprise then that &amp;ldquo;How to Win Friends And Influence People&amp;rdquo; is considered the social-etiquette bible by marketers, politicians, and snake salesmen the world over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carnegie lays out his principles in long-form, punctuated with his own observations of human behaviour and practical examples drawn from his lifetime of tutoring and mentorship in the field of human relations. This approach helps to solidify the foundations and assumptions of each principle, and give the reader an idea as to its applicability in everyday life; before driving the point home with a concise summary of the principle at the end of each chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few sample principles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t criticize, condemn, or complain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carnegie notes that humans react better to praise and positive remarks than they do criticism. For example, a foreman at a construction site may remark:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;WEAR YOUR GODDAMN HARDHATS, OR I&amp;rsquo;LL FIRE YOU FOR VIOLATING SITE POLICY!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or, he may say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Please make sure to wear your hardhats - it would kill me if anything happened to you!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is obvious to see that the tactful approach that expresses concern for the worker&amp;rsquo;s safety is likely to be the most effective, because it does not criticize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk in terms of the other person&amp;rsquo;s interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another fairly simple principle at heart, but an important one - the idea that one ought to build rapport with others by being genuinely interested in what they are interested in, and by being willing and able to give them what they desire. The most poignant example of this in my opinion is given in Part 2 Chapter 1, where Charles R. Walters requires information from the president. Charles takes note of the fact that the president&amp;rsquo;s son collects stamps, acquires some rare ones from across the globe, and spends an hour discussing stamps and the president&amp;rsquo;s son. At the end of the session, the president is more than happy to help him with all the information he needs. In essence this principle is: &amp;ldquo;Ask not what others can do for you, but what you can do for others&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throw down a challenge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carnegie realises that few people can resist a good bit of competition - a principle that is sadly overlooked in the modern era of consensus-building and &amp;ldquo;collaborative working environments&amp;rdquo;. People are driven to excel when they feel they have something to prove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give the other person a fine reputation to live up to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Assume a virtue, if you have it not&amp;rdquo; - Shakespeare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People have an inherent desire to be respected and reputable. If you praise someone on a virtue or skill, they will work extra hard to attempt to maintain the opinion they think you have of them - even if they don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily possess these qualities in the first place!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, finally, a principle that underlies Carnegie&amp;rsquo;s entire book:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be genuinely interested in people&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the book, all of Carnegie&amp;rsquo;s principles reference back to this one, overarching theme - from &amp;ldquo;be sympathetic&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;allow the other person to save face&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;begin with praise and appreciation&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;call attention to mistakes indirectly&amp;rdquo;, each rule is based on a solid foundation of being aware of and concerned with the other person&amp;rsquo;s wellbeing, feelings, and reputation. Even perhaps the simplest and most obvious rule in the book, &amp;ldquo;smile&amp;rdquo;, is difficult if not impossible if one is unable to adhere to this principle in his dealings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How To Win Friends And Influence People&amp;rdquo; is a decent primer for improving your interpersonal skills in professional environments, and may find applicability in the political sphere in terms of finding benefactors or schmoozing political allies, but the techniques described are limited in the sense that they are unlikely to persuade or influence someone who is decidedly opposed to you in the first instance, and require concerted practice to master.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;choice-quotes&#34;&gt;Choice quotes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-16&#34;&gt;Page 16&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“For years I have kept an engagement book showing all the appointments I had during the day. My family never made any plans for me on Saturday night, for the family knew that I devoted a part of each Saturday evening to the illuminating process of self-examination and review and appraisal. After dinner I went off by myself, opened my engagement book, and thought over all the interviews, discussions and meetings that had taken place during the week. I asked myself: “‘What mistakes did I make that time?’ “‘What did I do that was right—and in what way could I have improved my performance?’ “‘What lessons can I learn from that experience?’ “I often found that this weekly review made me very unhappy. I was frequently astonished at my own blunders. Of course, as the years passed, these blunders became less frequent. Sometimes I was inclined to pat myself on the back a little after one of these sessions. This system of self-analysis, self-education, continued year after year, did more for me than any other one thing I have ever attempted. “It helped me improve my ability to make decisions—and it aided me enormously in all my contacts with people. I cannot recommend it too highly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-28&#34;&gt;Page 28&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When dealing with people, let us remember we are not dealing with creatures of logic. We are dealing with creatures of emotion, creatures bristling with prejudices and motivated by pride and vanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-122&#34;&gt;Page 122&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can be sure of being right only 55 percent of the time, you can go down to Wall Street and make a million dollars a day. If you can’t be sure of being right even 55 percent of the time, why should you tell other people they are wrong?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-123&#34;&gt;Page 123&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Lord Chesterfield said to his son: Be wiser than other people if you can; but do not tell them so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-124&#34;&gt;Page 124&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s magic, positive magic, in such phrases as: “I may be wrong. I frequently am. Let’s examine the facts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-153&#34;&gt;Page 153&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Socrates, “the gadfly of Athens,” was one of the greatest philosophers the world has ever known. He did something that only a handful of men in all history have been able to do: he sharply changed the whole course of human thought; and now, twenty-four centuries after his death, he is honored as one of the wisest persuaders who ever influenced this wrangling world. His method? Did he tell people they were wrong? Oh, no, not Socrates. He was far too adroit for that. His whole technique, now called the “Socratic method,” was based upon getting a “yes, yes” response. He asked questions with which his opponent would have to agree. He kept on winning one admission after another until he had an armful of yeses. He kept on asking questions until finally, almost without realizing it, his opponents found themselves embracing a conclusion they would have bitterly denied a few minutes previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-154&#34;&gt;Page 154&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chinese have a proverb pregnant with the age-old wisdom of the Orient: “He who treads softly goes far.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-162&#34;&gt;Page 162&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ralph Waldo Emerson in his essay “Self-Reliance” stated: “In every work of genius we recognize our own rejected thoughts; they come back to us with a certain alienated majesty.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-187&#34;&gt;Page 187&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“All men have fears, but the brave put down their fears and go forward, sometimes to death, but always to victory” was the motto of the King’s Guard in ancient Greece. What greater challenge can be offered than the opportunity to overcome those fears?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-223&#34;&gt;Page 223&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Childish? Perhaps. But that is what they said to Napoleon when he created the Legion of Honor and distributed 15,000 crosses to his soldiers and made eighteen of his generals “Marshals of France” and called his troops the “Grand Army.” Napoleon was criticized for giving “toys” to war-hardened veterans, and Napoleon replied, “Men are ruled by toys.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club: Struggle for Berlin by Joseph Goebbels</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/struggle_for_berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 09:41:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/struggle_for_berlin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/struggle_for_berlin.pdf&#34;&gt;Link to PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/struggle_for_berlin.epub&#34;&gt;Link to epub (poor quality)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Struggle For Berlin by Joseph Goebbels is a personal account of events throughout the late 1920s and into the
early 1930s Germany regarding the NSDAP movement in Prussia in general and Berlin in particular. Throughout the
book, Goebbels frequently discusses the issues and challenges he faces as a district leader of the party as well as
writing about how he was able to overcome these issues. Many parallels can be drawn between the issues faced
by Goebbels and the issues faced today by many fringe political movements and regardless of if one agrees with
the author his account of events, intentional or otherwise, may make for excellent advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goebbels comes off as surprisingly charming for a clubfoot manlet and this is in no doubt to his ambition early in
life to become an author which were put on hold following the failure of two plays he wrote in ‘23. By 1940 he
would have 14 books under his belt, I suppose dreams do come true after all. Goebbels charm would go on to
serve him well in acquiring the position of chief propagandist for the Third Reich.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;selected-quotes&#34;&gt;Selected Quotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-17&#34;&gt;Page 17&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern propaganda as well rests in essence on the effect of the spoken word. Revolutionary movements are not
made by great writers, rather by great speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-14&#34;&gt;Page 14&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Socialism such as we understand it is essentially the result of a healthy feeling of justice, tied to a consciousness of
responsibility toward the nation, without regard for the “interests of an individual&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-40&#34;&gt;Page 40&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poster and assembly propaganda doubtlessly promised a better effect. But they as well, applied in the same style
as the other parties were accustomed, would have hardly brought successes of significant magnitude. For the
other parties were firmly anchored in the masses, after all. The political camps had already become so encrusted
toward each other that it was hardly possible to chip parts off from them. We hence had to make the attempt to
replace the lack of financial means and numeric following with amusing originality adapted to the thinking of the
Berlin populace. It was about appealing as much as possible to the fine understanding of the Berlin populace for
pointed formulations and effective slogans. We started with it early and, as the later development showed, it did
not remain without success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-11&#34;&gt;Page 11&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The struggle for the capital always forms a special chapter in the history of revolutionary movements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-159&#34;&gt;Page 159&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That would hardly move him inwardly. Stare at him hard and calm for a while and then say to him; ”You are
presumably a Jew!” And you will notice with amazement how unsure, how embarrassed and guilt ridden he
becomes at the same moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-71&#34;&gt;Page 71&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among nationalist writers, I usually had the impression that, quite the opposite, they wanted to put our
organization into the service of their pens. And hence for me, the verdict over them was pronounced from the
start. Above all, they seemed to lack the necessary civil courage. One was afraid to discredit oneself among the
civilization literati. It is the fear of the educated philistine, who does not dare to protest against whatever Jewish
insanity out of fear of appearing not modern and being ridiculed as untimely. Nationalism will always be decried by
the civilization literati as reactionary. One must then simply summon up the civil courage to shout it into the hacks
in the editorial offices: if nationalism is in their opinion reactionary, then we are just in God’s name reactionaries.
But we are in no way ready to allow our worldview to be prescribed for us by egotistical, excessively arrogant
cattle of the pen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club: The Fourth Political Theory by Alexander Dugin</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/the_fourth_political_theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 11:49:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/the_fourth_political_theory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/the_fourth_political_theory.epub&#34;&gt;Link to epub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/the_fourth_political_theory.pdf&#34;&gt;Link to PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-fourth-political-thoery---fascism-with-a-few-extra-steps&#34;&gt;The Fourth Political Thoery - Fascism with a few extra steps&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author attempts to build a foundation to a fourth political theory against Liberalism but mostly rambles in his attempts to do so. However, in these attempts, he provides an engaging analysis and criticism of Liberalism, Communism and Fascism. It is in this analysis that the book shines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is a second type of conservatism, which we have called status-quo or liberal conservatism. It is liberal because it says ‘yes’ to the main trend that is realised in modernity. But at each stage of this trend, it attempts to step on the brakes: ‘Let’s go slower, let’s not do that now, let’s postpone that.’&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Published in 2012 the author was ahead of his time in some ways. As seen above, Sasha provides an early look into what we now know as the &amp;ldquo;cuck-servative&amp;rdquo;. He similarly mocks Communism for having become an alternate reality game popular with the young bourgeoise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When critiquing fascism Sasha makes a fatal mistake. He attempts to separate the Racism inherent to Fascism, without proper regard for its inclusion. In short, his analysis completely overlooks Racism being hilarious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From what can be deciphered Dugin proposes an amalgamation of the strengths of communism and fascism. The result is an &amp;ldquo;anti-racist&amp;rdquo; endorsement for segregation, an embrace of collective identity and an appeal to the value of tradition. Also known as fascism with a few extra steps and a spot of paint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the book fails in its intended objective, it remains a recommended read. Though you&amp;rsquo;ll want to skim the weaker chapters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;selected-passages&#34;&gt;Selected Passages&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is now safe to institute a political program that was once outlawed by modernity. It no longer appears as foolish and doomed for failure as before, because everything in postmodernity looks foolish and doomed for failure, including its most ‘glamorous’ aspects. It is not by chance that the heroes of postmodernity are ‘freaks’ and ‘monsters’ ,’transvestites’ and ‘degenerates’ — this is the law of style. Against the backdrop of the world’s clowns, nothing and no one could look ‘too archaic’, not even the people of Tradition who ignore the imperatives of modern life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ideology of progress represents the moral genocide of past generations — in other words, real racism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, its own attempts to understand itself lead to failure. The first and the most prominent contradiction is Marx’s unfulfilled prediction about the type of societies that are the most prone to socialist revolutions. He was confident that this would take place in the greatly industrialised countries of Western Europe, which had a high level of manufacturing and contained a large proportion of urban proletariat. Such revolutions were considered impossible in agrarian countries, as well as those countries with an ‘Asiatic’ mode of production, due to their supposed backwardness. In the Twentieth century, everything occurred exactly to the contrary. Socialist revolutions and socialist societies developed in agrarian countries which had a traditional, rural population, while nothing similar occurred in any of the highly developed nations of Europe and America.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the postmodern gender? It is a maximisation of ‘the liberal man’, the archetype of which applies to all of its antitheses: the stupid, the poor, the non-White, the little, and so forth. It is also the gender of globalisation, when the properties of a certain type are extended as social standards onto all other types as universalism. Hence the idea that the proletarians are only the bourgeoisie who have not grown rich yet, Blacks are unmodernised whites, and women are not yet fully liberated men.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One of the theorists of the Conservative Revolution was Arthur Moeller van den Bruck, whose book was recently translated into Russian. Other thinkers who belonged to this tendency were Martin Heidegger, the brothers Ernst and Friedrich Jünger, Carl Schmitt, Oswald Spengler, Werner Sombart, Othmar Spann, Friedrich Hielscher, Ernst Niekisch and a whole constellation of mostly German authors, who are sometimes called ‘the dissidents of National Socialism’, because the majority of them, at some stage, supported National Socialism, but soon found themselves in a state of internal emigration, or even in jail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club: The Enchiridion by Epictetus</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/the_enchiridion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 19:43:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/the_enchiridion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/the_enchiridion.epub&#34;&gt;Link to epub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/the_enchiridion.pdf&#34;&gt;Link to PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-great-greek-book-of-cope-the-coperidium&#34;&gt;The Great Greek Book of Cope: The Coperidium&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nietzsche presented us with two fundamental types of morality: Master and Slave morality. The Enchiridion&amp;rsquo;s championing
of dispassion falls plainly within the realm of Slave morality. Though that is not to say the book has nothing to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core takeaway is to focus on our own actions, that which is within our control. As to that which is outside our control, we can only control our perception of them. From this core idea, emerges the corollary that happiness comes
from within, we attain it by deriving happiness only from what is within our control. That is, by letting go of the desire for that which is outside our reach. From this perspective, a critical opinion of ambition appears wise. Or is it just cope?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Enchiridion provides a framework for accepting difficult failures. From withdrawing your emotional attachment to outcomes to rejecting what is outside your influence to focus on what options are realistically available. Where the book falters is in an early contradiction - do not be averse to what is outside your control, and let go of desire to avoid disappointment. However, a life truly without desire is not possible, hence a life without failure or disappointment is similarly impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking a cue from The Enchiridion, we can choose to view failure as a learning experience rather than something harmful.
To accept the dice however they happen to fall. Having the toolkit to make the best of failure sets a foundation
from which we can pursue our desires with genuine effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where the Enchiridion would have you avoid disappointment, I would rather have the strength of character to endure it. Even with these
flaws, the book remains an interesting collection of wisdom and a worthwhile read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;selected-passages&#34;&gt;Selected Passages&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remove aversion, then, from all things that are not in our control, and transfer it to things contrary to the nature of what is in our control. But, for the present, totally suppress desire: for, if you desire any of the things which are not in your own control, you must necessarily be disappointed; and of those which are, and which it would be laudable to desire, nothing is yet in your possession. Use only the appropriate actions of pursuit and avoidance;and even these lightly, and with gentleness and reservation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a person gave your body to any stranger he met on his way, you would certainly be angry. And do you feel no shame in handing over your own mind to be confused and mystified by anyone who happens to verbally attack you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With every accident, ask yourself what abilities you have for making a proper use of it. If you see an attractive person, you will find that self-restraint is the ability you have against your desire.If you are in pain, you will find fortitude. If you hear unpleasant language, you will find patience. And thus habituated, the appearances of things will not hurry you away along with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When any person harms you, or speaks badly of you, remember tha the acts or speaks from a supposition of its being his duty. Now, it is not possible that he should follow what appears right to you, but what appears so to himself. Therefore, if he judges from a wrong appearance, he is the person hurt, since he too is the person deceived. For if anyone should suppose a true proposition to be false, the proposition is not hurt, but he who is deceived about it. Setting out, then, from these principles, you will meekly bear a person who reviles you, for you will say upon every occasion, &amp;ldquo;It seemed so to him.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For sheep don&amp;rsquo;t throw up the grass to show the shepherds how much they have eaten; but, inwardly digesting their food, they outwardly produce wool and milk. Thus, therefore, do you likewise not show theorems to the unlearned, but the actions produced by them after they have been digested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club: The Abolition of Man by C.S. Lewis</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/the_abolition_of_man/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 10:41:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/the_abolition_of_man/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/the_abolition_of_man.epub&#34;&gt;Link to epub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/the_abolition_of_man.pdf&#34;&gt;Link to PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;selected-passages&#34;&gt;Selected Passages&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;illustrations-of-the-tao&#34;&gt;Illustrations of the Tao&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-law-of-general-beneficence&#34;&gt;The Law of General Beneficence&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nature urges that a man should wish human society to exist and should wish to enter it.’ (Roman. Cicero, De Officiis, 1. iv)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do to men what you wish men to do to you.’ (Christian. Matthew 7:12)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-law-of-special-beneficence&#34;&gt;The Law of Special Beneficence&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it only the sons of Atreus who love their wives? For every good man, who is right-minded, loves and cherishes his own.’ (Greek. Homer, Iliad, ix. 340)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The union and fellowship of men will be best preserved if each receives from us the more kindness in proportion as he is more closely connected with us.’ (Roman. Cicero. De Off. 1. xvi)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Part of us is claimed by our country, part by our parents, part by our friends.’ (Roman. Ibid. 1. vii)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;duties-to-parents-elders-ancestors&#34;&gt;Duties to Parents, Elders, Ancestors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;‘I was a staff by my Father’s side . . . I went in and out athis  command.’  (Ancient  Egyptian.  Confession  of  theRighteous Soul. EREv.  481)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;‘To care for parents.’ (Greek. List of duties in Epictetus,111. vii)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;duties-to-children-and-posterity&#34;&gt;Duties to Children and Posterity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;‘To marry and to beget children.’ (Greek. List of duties.Epictetus,111. vii)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;‘Nature produces a special love of offspring’ and ‘To liveaccording  to  Nature  is  the  supreme  good.’  (Roman.Cicero,De Off.1. iv, and De Legibus,1. xxi)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;‘The  killing  of  the  women  and  more  especially  of  theyoung  boys  and  girls  who  are  to  go  to  make  up  thefuture strength of the people, is the saddest part, we feel it very sorely.’ (Redskin. Account of the Battleof Wounded Knee. EREv.  432)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-law-of-justice&#34;&gt;The Law of Justice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;‘Has  he  approached  his  neighbour’s  wife?’  (Babylonian.List of Sins. EREv.  446)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;‘Choose loss rather than shameful gains.’ (Greek. ChilonFr. 10. Diels)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-law-of-good-faith-and-veracity&#34;&gt;The Law of Good Faith and Veracity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;‘I  sought  no  trickery,  nor  swore  false  oaths.’  (Anglo-Saxon.Beowulf,2738)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-law-of-mercy&#34;&gt;The Law of Mercy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;‘They said that he had been the mildest and gentlest of thekings of the world.’ (Anglo-Saxon. Praise of the hero in Beowulf,3180)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-law-of-magnanimity&#34;&gt;The Law of Magnanimity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;‘There are two kinds of injustice: the first is found in thosewho do an injury, the second in those who fail to pro-tect  another  from  injury  when  they  can.’  (Roman.Cicero,De Off.1. vii)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;‘Men always knew that when force and injury was offered they might be defenders of themselves; they knew thathowsoever men may seek their own commodity, yet if this were done with injury unto others it was not to besuffered, but by all men and by all good means to be with-stood.’ (English. Hooker, Laws of Eccl. Polity,1. ix. 4)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;‘Courage  has  got  to  be  harder,  heart  the  stouter,  spirit the  sterner,  as  our  strength  weakens.  Here  lies  ourlord, cut to pieces, out best man in the dust. If anyone thinks  of  leaving  this  battle,  he  can  howl  forever.’(Anglo-Saxon.Maldon,312)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;‘Death  is  to  be  chosen  before  slavery  and  base  deeds.’(Roman. Cicero, De Off.1, xxiii)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;‘Death  is  better  for  every  man  than  life  with  shame.’(Anglo-Saxon.Beowulf,2890)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;‘The Master said, Love learning and if attacked be ready to die for the Good Way.’ (Ancient Chinese. Analects,viii.13)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;selected-quotes&#34;&gt;Selected Quotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chinese also speak of a great thing (the greatest thing) called the Tao. It is the reality beyond all predicates, the abyss that was before the Creator Himself. It is Nature, it is the Way, the Road. It is the Way in which the universe goes on, the Way in which things everlastingly emerge, stilly and tranquilly, into space and time. It is also the Way which every man should tread in imitation of that cosmic and supercosmic progression, conforming all activities to that great exemplar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a Roman father told his son that it was a sweet and seemly thing to die for his country, he believed what he said. He was communicating to the son an emotion which he himself shared and which he believed to be in accord with the value which his judgement discerned in noble death. He was giving the boy the best he had, giving of his spirit to humanize him as he had given of his body to beget him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can hardly open a periodical without coming across the statement that what our civilization needs is more ‘drive’, or dynamism, or self-sacrifice, or ‘creativity’. In a sort of ghastly simplicity we remove the organ and demand the function. We make men without chests and expect of them virtue and enterprise. We laugh at honour and are shocked to find traitors in our midst. We castrate and bid the geldings be fruitful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it cannot strictly be said that when he does so he is exercising his own proper or individual power over Nature. If I pay you to carry me, I am not therefore myself a strong man. Any or all of the three things I have mentioned can be withheld from some men by other men—by those who sell, or those who allow the sale, or those who own the sources of production, or those who make the goods. What we call Man’s power is, in reality, a power possessed by some men which they may, or may not, allow other men to profit by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the questions before them is whether this feeling for posterity (they know well how it is produced) shall be continued or not. However far they go back, or down, they can find no ground to stand on. Every motive they try to act on becomes at once a petitio. It is not that they are bad men. They are not men at all. Stepping outside the Tao, they have stepped into the void. Nor are their subjects necessarily unhappy men. They are not men at all: they are artefacts. Man’s final conquest has proved to be the abolition of Man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up to that point, the kind of explanation which explains things away may give us something, though at a heavy cost. But you cannot go on ‘explaining away’ for ever: you will find that you have explained explanation itself away. You cannot go on ‘seeing through’ things for ever. The whole point of seeing through something is to see something through it. It is good that the window should be transparent, because the street or garden beyond it is opaque. How if you saw through the garden too? It is no use trying to ‘see through’ first principles. If you see through everything, then everything is transparent. But a wholly transparent world is an invisible world. To ‘see through’ all things is the same as not to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club: Rules for Radicals by Saul Alinsky</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/rules_for_radicals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 16:11:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/rules_for_radicals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/rules_for_radicals.epub&#34;&gt;Link to epub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rules for Radicals is a window into the famous Jewish revolutionary spirit. A great read. It touches on morals,
mindset and tactics. Both Nietzsche and Machiavelli make unexpected appearances. A recommended read to dissidents of
any persuasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;selected-passages&#34;&gt;Selected Passages&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rules-to-the-ethics-of-means-and-ends&#34;&gt;Rules to the Ethics of Means and Ends&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One&amp;rsquo;s concern with the ethics of means and ends varies inversely with one&amp;rsquo;s personal interest in the issue. One&amp;rsquo;s
concern with the ethics of means and ends varies inversely with one&amp;rsquo;s distance from the scene of conflict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second rule of the ethics of means and ends is that the judgment of the ethics of means is dependent upon the
political position of those sitting in judgment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third rule of the ethics of means and ends is that in war the end justifies almost any means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fourth rule of the ethics of means and ends is that judgment must be made in the context of the times in which
the action occurred and not from any other chronological vantage point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fifth rule of the ethics of means and ends is that concern with ethics increases with the number of means
available and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sixth rule of the ethics of means and ends is that the less important the end to be desired, the more one can
afford to engage in ethical evaluations of means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The seventh rule of the ethics of means and ends is that generally success or failure is a mighty determinant of
ethics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The eighth rule of the ethics of means and ends is that the morality of a means depends upon whether the means
is being employed at a time of imminent defeat or imminent victory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ninth rule of the ethics of means and ends is that any effective means is automatically judged by the opposition
as being unethical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The tenth rule of the ethics of means and ends is that you do what you can with what you have and clothe it with
moral garments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The eleventh rule of the ethics of means and ends is that goals must be phrased in general terms like &amp;ldquo;Liberty,
Equality, Fraternity,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Of the Common Welfare,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Pursuit of Happiness,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Bread and Peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rules-for-power-tactics&#34;&gt;Rules for Power Tactics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Power is not only what you have but what the enemy thinks you have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second rule is: Never go outside the experience of your people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third rule is: Wherever possible go outside of the experience of the enemy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fourth rule is: Make the enemy live up to their own book of rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fourth rule carries within it the fifth rule: Ridicule is mans most potent weapon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sixth rule is: A good tactic is one that your people enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The seventh rule: A tactic that drags on too long becomes a drag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The eighth rule: Keep the pressure on, with different tactics and actions, and utilize all events of the period for your purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ninth rule: The threat is usually more terrifying than the thing itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tenth rule: The major premise for tactics is the development of operations that will maintain a constant pressure upon the opposition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The eleventh rule is: If you push a negative hard and deep enough it will break through into its counterside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The twelfth rule: The price of a successful attack is a constructive alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thirteenth rule: Pick the target, freeze it, personalize it, and polarize it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;selected-quotes&#34;&gt;Selected Quotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave the young radicals seemed to me the only realistic one: &amp;ldquo;Do one of three things. One, go find a wailing wall
and feel sorry for yourselves. Two, go psycho and start bombing—but this will only swing people to the right.
Three, learn a lesson. Go home, organize, build power and at the next convention, you be the delegates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A word about my personal philosophy. It is anchored in optimism. It must be, for optimism brings with it hope, a
future with a purpose, and therefore, a will to fight for a better world. Without this optimism, there is no reason
to carry on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The means-and-end moralists or non-doers always wind up on their ends without any means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machiavelli&amp;rsquo;s blindness to the necessity for moral clothing to all acts and motives—he said &amp;ldquo;politics has no relation
to morals&amp;rdquo;—was his major weakness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Democracy is not an end; it is the best political means available toward the achievement of these values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real action is in the enemy&amp;rsquo;s reaction.
The enemy properly goaded and guided in his reaction will be your major strength.
Tactics, like organization, like life, require that you move with the action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club: Bronze Age Mindset by Bronze Age Pervert</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/bronze_age_mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 09:54:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/bronze_age_mindset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/bronze_age_mindset.epub&#34;&gt;Link to epub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t let the authors poor grammar fool you, Bronze Age Mindset punches above its weight and is worth reading through
more than once. His style of writing is energetically humorous, and at times absurd. Highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bronze Age Pervert (BAP) builds heavily upon Nietzsche&amp;rsquo;s body of work, though he has several other notable influences.
Namely: Paglia, Schopenhauer, Machiavelli, and Mishima.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cautionary note&lt;/strong&gt;: Chimpanzees do in fact jerk off in nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;interesting-mentions&#34;&gt;Interesting Mentions:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;midnight-express&#34;&gt;Midnight Express&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Film about an American arrested for drug smuggling in Turkey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;john-miliushttpsenwikipediaorgwikijohn_miliuspersonal_life&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Milius#Personal_life&#34;&gt;John Milius&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Milius is a self-proclaimed &amp;ldquo;Zen anarchist&amp;rdquo;, but he also publicly aligns himself with conservative factions in Hollywood and he was interviewed in the documentary Rated R: Republicans in Hollywood. He has also been consultant to a military think tank, the Institute for Creative Technologies. Milius said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m not a reactionary—I&amp;rsquo;m just a right-wing extremist so far beyond the Christian Identity people like that and stuff, that they can&amp;rsquo;t even imagine. I&amp;rsquo;m so far beyond that I&amp;rsquo;m a Maoist. I&amp;rsquo;m an anarchist. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been an anarchist. Any true, real right-winger if he goes far enough hates all form of government, because government should be done to cattle and not human beings.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;deroshttpsanomaliencomderos-advanced-creatures-from-beneath-the-hollow-earth&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://anomalien.com/deros-advanced-creatures-from-beneath-the-hollow-earth/&#34;&gt;DEROS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some believers in the theory that Earth has a hollow (Hollow Earth), inhabitable core sometimes also believe in evil creatures called the Deros, which were supposedly created through genetic engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;wilhelm-reichhttpsenwikipediaorgwikiwilhelm_reich&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wilhelm_Reich&#34;&gt;Wilhelm Reich&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Described by Elizabeth Danto as a large man with a cantankerous style who managed to look scruffy and elegant at the same time, he tried to reconcile psychoanalysis with Marxism, arguing that neurosis is rooted in sexual and socio-economic conditions, and in particular in a lack of what he called &amp;ldquo;orgastic potency&amp;rdquo;.
He visited patients in their homes to see how they lived, and took to the streets in a mobile clinic, promoting adolescent sexuality and the availability of contraceptives, abortion and divorce, a provocative message in Catholic Austria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pre-hop-ale--beer&#34;&gt;Pre-hop ale / beer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zythophile.co.uk/2014/02/28/was-it-ever-gruit-britain-the-herb-ale-tradition/&#34;&gt;Mentioned by random beer blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;phantom-time-hypothesishttpsenwikipediaorgwikiphantom_time_hypothesis&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phantom_time_hypothesis&#34;&gt;Phantom time hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;margaret-meadhttpsenwikipediaorgwikimargaret_mead&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Margaret_Mead&#34;&gt;Margaret Mead&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freeman argued that Mead had misunderstood Samoan culture when she argued that Samoan culture did not place many restrictions on youths&amp;rsquo; sexual explorations.
While Mead was careful to shield the identity of all her subjects for confidentiality Freeman was able to find and interview one of her original participants, and Freeman reported that she admitted to having wilfully misled Mead. She said that she and her friends were having fun with Mead and telling her stories.
It&amp;rsquo;s still disputed whether her research is valid or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sacred-band-of-thebeshttpsenwikipediaorgwikisacred_band_of_thebes&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sacred_Band_of_Thebes&#34;&gt;Sacred Band of Thebes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mark-thatcherhttpsenwikipediaorgwikimark_thatcher&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mark_Thatcher&#34;&gt;Mark Thatcher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2005, he was convicted and given a four-year suspended prison sentence and a fine in South Africa for funding the 2004 Equatorial Guinea coup d&#39;état attempt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;glycine-and-theanine&#34;&gt;Glycine and Theanine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BAP describes his usages of these substances as if they were drugs giving him a high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dark-ocean-societyhttpsenwikipediaorgwikigen27yc58dsha&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gen%27y%C5%8Dsha&#34;&gt;Dark Ocean Society&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dark/Black Ocean Society was an influential Pan-Asianist group and secret society active in the Empire of Japan, and was considered to be an ultranationalist group by GHQ in the International Military Tribunal for the Far East.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;league-of-the-divine-wind---mishima&#34;&gt;League of the Divine Wind - Mishima&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;alcibiadeshttpsenwikipediaorgwikialcibiades&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alcibiades&#34;&gt;Alcibiades&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hippocleideshttpsenwikipediaorgwikihippocleides&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hippocleides&#34;&gt;Hippocleides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hippocleides doesn&amp;rsquo;t care&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ben-bernankehttpsenwikipediaorgwikiben_bernanke&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ben_Bernanke&#34;&gt;Ben Bernanke&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;they’ve been as a wit recently put it Bernankefied up the ass.&amp;rdquo; What means?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;clearchus-of-spartahttpsenwikipediaorgwikiclearchus_of_sparta&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clearchus_of_Sparta&#34;&gt;Clearchus of Sparta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;agathocleshttpswwwbritannicacombiographyagathocles&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.britannica.com/biography/Agathocles&#34;&gt;Agathocles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;wandervogelhttpsenwikipediaorgwikiwandervogel&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wandervogel&#34;&gt;Wandervogel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wandervogel is the name adopted by a popular movement of German youth groups from 1896 to 1933, who protested against industrialization by going to hike in the country and commune with nature in the woods. Drawing influence from medieval wandering scholars, their ethos was to revive old Teutonic values, with a strong emphasis on German nationalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bob-denardhttpsenwikipediaorgwikibob_denard&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bob_Denard&#34;&gt;Bob Denard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mad-mike-hoarehttpsenwikipediaorgwikimad_mike_hoare&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mad_Mike_Hoare&#34;&gt;Mad Mike Hoare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hommenhttpsfrwiktionaryorgwikihommen&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fr.wiktionary.org/wiki/Hommen&#34;&gt;Hommen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;review-by-a-buddhist&#34;&gt;Review by a Buddhist&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://politicallyincorrectdharma.blogspot.com/2021/06/bronze-age-mindset-nietzsche-vs-darwin.html&#34;&gt;Nietzsche vs Dawin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://politicallyincorrectdharma.blogspot.com/2021/06/bronze-age-mindset-more-or-less.html&#34;&gt;A more of less Buddhist response&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But despite his love of psychopathy and his accelerationism and militaristic/militant leanings, he does occasionally make good common sense, for example his observation that pure democracy is suicidal and a guarantee of disaster, especially if the population is &amp;lsquo;diverse.&#39;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;selected-quotes&#34;&gt;Selected Quotes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-82-paragraph-1&#34;&gt;Page 82, Paragraph 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The true environmentalism is racism and has a racial foundation, and in fact the two things, environmentalism and racism, are indistinguishable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-88&#34;&gt;Page 88&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saddam Hussein was like this: he was a transsexual in his soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-130&#34;&gt;Page 130&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among your instincts you will find the longing for strong friendships, that the modern evil tries to snuff out. And they have good reason to try this, because every great thing in the past was done through strong friendships between two men, or brotherhoods of men, and this includes all great political things, all acts of political freedom and power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-192&#34;&gt;Page 192&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The left realizes they look weak and lame—because they are. They know they have nothing to offer youth but submission and lectures. They know they&amp;rsquo;re unsexy and staid. If indeed young leftist men will start lifting and worshiping beauty, they will be forced to leave the left.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club: A History of Central Banking by Stephen Mitford Goodson</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/history_of_central_banking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 11:13:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/history_of_central_banking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/history_of_central_banking.epub&#34;&gt;Link to epub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bitchute.com/video/oVkI4tZvHebE/&#34;&gt;Link to Bitchute Audiobook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book makes many unsourced claims, and when it does provide sources they are frequently unreliable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, reading and verifying the claims in the book drew attention to a number of interesting events and ideas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chicago_plan#A_Program_for_Monetary_Reform&#34;&gt;The Chicago Plan&lt;/a&gt;: A proposal for
&amp;ldquo;full-reserve&amp;rdquo; banking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author is of the opinion that the Great Depression was intentionally caused by the Federal Reserve. Economist
Milton Friedman held a similar opinion,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://fee.org/articles/the-great-depression-according-to-milton-friedman/&#34;&gt;that they failed to perform their duty as a lender of last resort&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bank of England had the now dormant Bank of England Nominees which was exempt from the requirement
to declare the identities of their shareholders. The Guardian claims the Queen made use of it to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/feb/07/revealed-queen-lobbied-for-change-in-law-to-hide-her-private-wealth&#34;&gt;hide her private wealth&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gottfried Feder, the economist who attracted Hitler into the Nazi party, was an advocate for
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gottfried_Feder&#34;&gt;Garden Cities&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book has an interesting quote attributed to former Governor of The Bank of England Montagu Normal on &amp;ldquo;Capital
must protect itself&amp;rdquo;. It is mentioned even on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wsws.org/en/articles/2012/05/corr-m15.html&#34;&gt;The World Socialist Web Site&lt;/a&gt;.
As far as I can tell it is &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Talk:J._P._Morgan&#34;&gt;fabricated&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book makes the unsourced claim that Trotsky was financed by America and Britain. I would very much like to know
if there is a reliable source for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;selected-quotes&#34;&gt;Selected Quotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bejamin-franklin-pg-60&#34;&gt;Bejamin Franklin (Pg 60)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is simple. In the colonies we issue our own money. It is called colonial script. We issue it in proportion to the demands of trade and industry to make the products pass easily from the producers to the consumers. In this manner, creating for ourselves our own money, we control its purchasing power, and we have no interest to pay anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;james-abram-garfield-pg-71&#34;&gt;James Abram Garfield (Pg 71)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whosoever controls the volume of money in any country is absolute master of all industry and commerce&amp;hellip; And when you realise that the entire system is very easily controlled, one way or another, by a few powerful men at the top, you will not have to be told how periods of inflation and depression originate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club: Sun and Steel by Yukio Mishima</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/sun_and_steel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 09:24:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/sun_and_steel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/sun_and_steel.epub&#34;&gt;Link to epub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ikfv8YgFIZE&#34;&gt;Link to Youtube Audiobook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;selected-quotes&#34;&gt;Selected Quotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-4-pg-36&#34;&gt;Chapter 4, Pg 36&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Success comes when both the timing and placing of the blow are just right. But more than this, it happens when the choice of time and target—one’s judgement—manages to catch the foe momentarily off guard, when one has an intuitive apprehension of that off-guard moment a fraction of a second before it becomes perceptible to the senses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-7-pg-58&#34;&gt;Chapter 7, Pg 58&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How ironical it was! At a period when the futureless cup of catastrophe had been brimming over, I had not been given the qualifications for drinking from it. I had gone away, and when, after long training, I had returned armed with those qualifications in fullest measure, it was to find the cup drained, its bottom coldly visible, and myself past forty. Unfortunately, moreover, the only liquid that might quench my thirst was that which others had drained before me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-10-pg-83&#34;&gt;Chapter 10, Pg 83&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only through the group, I realized—through sharing the suffering of the group—could the body reach that height of existence that the individual alone could never attain. And for the body to reach that level at which the divine might be glimpsed, a dissolution of the individuality was necessary. The tragic quality of the group was also necessary—the quality that constantly raised the group out of the abandon and torpor into which it was prone to lapse, leading it on to ever-mounting shared suffering and so to death, which was the ultimate suffering. The group must be open to death—which meant, of course, that it must be a community of warriors&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the dim light of early morning I was running, one of a group. A cotton towel with the symbol of a red sun on it was tied about my forehead, and I was stripped to the waist in the freezing air. Through the common suffering, the shared cries of encouragement, the shared pace, and the chorus of voices, I felt the slow emergence, like the sweat that gradually beaded my skin, of that “tragic” quality that is the affirmation of identity. It was a flame of the flesh, flickering up faintly beneath the biting breeze—a flame, one might almost say, of nobility. The sense of surrendering one’s body to a cause gave new life to the muscles. We were united in seeking death and glory; it was not merely my personal quest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
