<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on The RDK</title>
    <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on The RDK</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 19:40:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://the-rdk.github.io/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Always the Horizon by Murdoch Murdoch</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/always_the_horizon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 19:40:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/always_the_horizon/</guid>
      <description>Link to PDF</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Win Friends and Influence People by Dale Carnegie</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/how_to_win_friends_and_influence_people/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 19:25:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/how_to_win_friends_and_influence_people/</guid>
      <description>Link to PDF
Link to epub
&amp;ldquo;How to Win Friends And Influence People&amp;rdquo; by Dale Carnegie is a one-stop-shop for aspiring used car salesmen and middle managers to attain mastery in the laudable art of brown-nosing. The reader may at first consider the rules and principles laid out in this book rather simple, but as with Newton&amp;rsquo;s laws of motion and Pythagoras&amp;rsquo; theorem, Carnegie was the first to write them down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Struggle for Berlin by Joseph Goebbels</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/struggle_for_berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 09:41:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/struggle_for_berlin/</guid>
      <description>Link to PDF
Link to epub (poor quality)
The Struggle For Berlin by Joseph Goebbels is a personal account of events throughout the late 1920s and into the early 1930s Germany regarding the NSDAP movement in Prussia in general and Berlin in particular. Throughout the book, Goebbels frequently discusses the issues and challenges he faces as a district leader of the party as well as writing about how he was able to overcome these issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fourth Political Theory by Alexander Dugin</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/the_fourth_political_theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 11:49:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/the_fourth_political_theory/</guid>
      <description>Link to epub
Link to PDF
The Fourth Political Thoery - Fascism with a few extra steps The author attempts to build a foundation to a fourth political theory against Liberalism but mostly rambles in his attempts to do so. However, in these attempts, he provides an engaging analysis and criticism of Liberalism, Communism and Fascism. It is in this analysis that the book shines.
&amp;ldquo;There is a second type of conservatism, which we have called status-quo or liberal conservatism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Enchiridion by Epictetus</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/the_enchiridion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 19:43:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/the_enchiridion/</guid>
      <description>Link to epub
Link to PDF
The Great Greek Book of Cope: The Coperidium Nietzsche presented us with two fundamental types of morality: Master and Slave morality. The Enchiridion&amp;rsquo;s championing of dispassion falls plainly within the realm of Slave morality. Though that is not to say the book has nothing to offer.
The core takeaway is to focus on our own actions, that which is within our control. As to that which is outside our control, we can only control our perception of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Abolition of Man by C.S. Lewis</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/the_abolition_of_man/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 10:41:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/the_abolition_of_man/</guid>
      <description>Link to epub
Link to PDF
Selected Passages Illustrations of the Tao The Law of General Beneficence  Nature urges that a man should wish human society to exist and should wish to enter it.’ (Roman. Cicero, De Officiis, 1. iv) Do to men what you wish men to do to you.’ (Christian. Matthew 7:12)  The Law of Special Beneficence  Is it only the sons of Atreus who love their wives?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rules for Radicals by Saul Alinsky</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/rules_for_radicals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 16:11:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/rules_for_radicals/</guid>
      <description>Link to epub
Rules for Radicals is a window into the famous Jewish revolutionary spirit. A great read. It touches on morals, mindset and tactics. Both Nietzsche and Machiavelli make unexpected appearances. A recommended read to dissidents of any persuasion.
Selected Passages Rules to the Ethics of Means and Ends  One&amp;rsquo;s concern with the ethics of means and ends varies inversely with one&amp;rsquo;s personal interest in the issue. One&amp;rsquo;s concern with the ethics of means and ends varies inversely with one&amp;rsquo;s distance from the scene of conflict.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bronze Age Mindset by Bronze Age Pervert</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/bronze_age_mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 09:54:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/bronze_age_mindset/</guid>
      <description>Link to epub
Don&amp;rsquo;t let the authors poor grammar fool you, Bronze Age Mindset punches above its weight and is worth reading through more than once. His style of writing is energetically humorous, and at times absurd. Highly recommended.
Bronze Age Pervert (BAP) builds heavily upon Nietzsche&amp;rsquo;s body of work, though he has several other notable influences. Namely: Paglia, Schopenhauer, Machiavelli, and Mishima.
Cautionary note: Chimpanzees do in fact jerk off in nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A History of Central Banking by Stephen Mitford Goodson</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/history_of_central_banking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 11:13:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/history_of_central_banking/</guid>
      <description>Link to epub
Link to Bitchute Audiobook
The book makes many unsourced claims, and when it does provide sources they are frequently unreliable.
However, reading and verifying the claims in the book drew attention to a number of interesting events and ideas:
 The Chicago Plan: A proposal for &amp;ldquo;full-reserve&amp;rdquo; banking.
 The author is of the opinion that the Great Depression was intentionally caused by the Federal Reserve. Economist Milton Friedman held a similar opinion, that they failed to perform their duty as a lender of last resort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sun and Steel by Yukio Mishima</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/sun_and_steel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 09:24:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/sun_and_steel/</guid>
      <description>Link to epub
Link to Youtube Audiobook
Selected Quotes Chapter 4, Pg 36 Success comes when both the timing and placing of the blow are just right. But more than this, it happens when the choice of time and target—one’s judgement—manages to catch the foe momentarily off guard, when one has an intuitive apprehension of that off-guard moment a fraction of a second before it becomes perceptible to the senses.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>