<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Caledonian on The RDK</title>
    <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/authors/caledonian/</link>
    <description>The RDK (Caledonian)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 19:40:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://the-rdk.github.io/authors/caledonian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club: Always the Horizon by Murdoch Murdoch</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/always_the_horizon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 19:40:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/always_the_horizon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/always_the_horizon.pdf&#34;&gt;Link to PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Always The Horizon&amp;rsquo; by Murdoch Murdoch is the pseudonymous screenwriter&amp;rsquo;s first foray into a work of a more formal nature. While this fact may often be apparent in the text, with some staccato action sequences reading more like directions for an animator as opposed to a novella, Murdoch is effective in expressing the same hopeful ideals he portrays in his web animations in this new prosaic form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking cues from Nietzsche&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Thus Spake Zarathustra&amp;rsquo;, Greek mythology, gothic horror and fantasy stories, Murdoch encourages readers to fight against nihilism and despair. Instead, find joy in imagining Sisyphus happy: striving to be the best person you can be, finding meaning in overcoming the challenges you face, and eternally running towards the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Murdoch rejects the cold, analytical fatalism endemic in modern society in favour of a romantic, perhaps even foolish, idealism. This is reflected even in the name of the protagonist, as the story is framed as a dialogue between The Sacred Clown and his faithful horse-riding companion, surrogates respectively for Murdoch and the reader himself, as they embark on a classic hero&amp;rsquo;s journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the tale, Murdoch also touches on a variety of issues the modern world faces: the futility of captured &amp;ldquo;democratic&amp;rdquo; systems, relations between the sexes, the failures of modern religion, death, and the parasitic forces of dissolution who prioritise their own selfish greed over higher ideals. The second-person narration draws the reader into the text as if Murdoch is speaking to us directly, and sections of text preceded with a dramatic &amp;ldquo;Know this:&amp;rdquo; serve to drive home the points Murdoch is attempting to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crux of Always The Horizon is a message of hope - that we might meet the world on its own terms with the same knowing glint in our eye as one might find in the eye of a Hindu guru. A knowledge that transcends nihilism and declares &amp;ldquo;nothing matters - so what!&amp;rdquo; - that the journey itself is enough to fulfil a man. And in that, at least, Murdoch echoes philosophers and priests throughout the ages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;quotes&#34;&gt;Quotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why have you come here, rider, to the grave of your fatherland? Have
you come to follow me? Know that I lead no man, but if you wish to
become my companion then I must make a single request of you. If
we are to take up this task and travel the all-too-arduous path, then
you must promise me that your eyes will remain transfixed, always,
on the horizon. There we will chase the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gnash my teeth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seventeen hundred years ago Constantine, curse his
name, undid all of the steps undertaken by Diocletian to hold on
to the memetic keys that the Romans had venerated since their
inception. Did these so-called “Romans” not realize that every step
further from mos maiorum was a step towards losing themselves?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let it be said that the new man will not
die for his own immortality, but rather will live for the continuation
of Being’s drive towards knowing – so that he may rest satisfied
on his death bed, secure in the knowledge that he took up the task
to aid truth’s pursuit of truth. Being to being. And that he like the
romantics who came before, and those who shall come after, chased
the sun with reckless abandon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know this, rider, hate is born from the womb of love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we make our escape we move to find higher ground, out towards
the mountain peaks. There we witness the metropolis in twilight,
finally submerged in the wave of the Nothing, completely lost to
time. Not even the grass that circled the walls of the city remains.
The landscape now resembles an alien world, devoid of life. The
insects and birds, men and women, the old and young, even the
streets and towers have been completely erased. But there, where
the lone soldier stood, lies a mound of debris – a small fragment of
the city wall, and the few moths that hover above, are now all that
remain of that once great city of light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man is a wolf to man. Great acts of unkindness run deep in all of our histories – or have you
forgotten the corpses that run alongside your Great Wall? You are
not my enemy, Liu Bei. You are only another aspect of Being. We are
both capable of the knowing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pub remains silent and I shout once more, “We shall ride under
lightning! For that was the weapon of Zeus and Jupiter and Taranis;
of Thor and Indra; of Perun, Perk  ̄unas, and Perkwunos! Let us become
wild men again! For you who dwell here, did I not ride alongside
you for years? Come with me again, let us ride out into the horizon!
Let us chase Sul, Helios, Arinna, Hvare-khshaeta, Surya and Sol
Invictus!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club: How to Win Friends and Influence People by Dale Carnegie</title>
      <link>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/how_to_win_friends_and_influence_people/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 19:25:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-rdk.github.io/book/how_to_win_friends_and_influence_people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/how_to_win_friends_and_influence_people.pdf&#34;&gt;Link to PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-rdk.github.io/books/how_to_win_friends_and_influence_people.epub&#34;&gt;Link to epub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How to Win Friends And Influence People&amp;rdquo; by Dale Carnegie is a one-stop-shop for aspiring used car salesmen and middle managers to attain mastery in the laudable art of brown-nosing. The reader may at first consider the rules and principles laid out in this book rather simple, but as with Newton&amp;rsquo;s laws of motion and Pythagoras&amp;rsquo; theorem, Carnegie was the first to write them down. It is hardly a surprise then that &amp;ldquo;How to Win Friends And Influence People&amp;rdquo; is considered the social-etiquette bible by marketers, politicians, and snake salesmen the world over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carnegie lays out his principles in long-form, punctuated with his own observations of human behaviour and practical examples drawn from his lifetime of tutoring and mentorship in the field of human relations. This approach helps to solidify the foundations and assumptions of each principle, and give the reader an idea as to its applicability in everyday life; before driving the point home with a concise summary of the principle at the end of each chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few sample principles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t criticize, condemn, or complain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carnegie notes that humans react better to praise and positive remarks than they do criticism. For example, a foreman at a construction site may remark:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;WEAR YOUR GODDAMN HARDHATS, OR I&amp;rsquo;LL FIRE YOU FOR VIOLATING SITE POLICY!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or, he may say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Please make sure to wear your hardhats - it would kill me if anything happened to you!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is obvious to see that the tactful approach that expresses concern for the worker&amp;rsquo;s safety is likely to be the most effective, because it does not criticize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk in terms of the other person&amp;rsquo;s interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another fairly simple principle at heart, but an important one - the idea that one ought to build rapport with others by being genuinely interested in what they are interested in, and by being willing and able to give them what they desire. The most poignant example of this in my opinion is given in Part 2 Chapter 1, where Charles R. Walters requires information from the president. Charles takes note of the fact that the president&amp;rsquo;s son collects stamps, acquires some rare ones from across the globe, and spends an hour discussing stamps and the president&amp;rsquo;s son. At the end of the session, the president is more than happy to help him with all the information he needs. In essence this principle is: &amp;ldquo;Ask not what others can do for you, but what you can do for others&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throw down a challenge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carnegie realises that few people can resist a good bit of competition - a principle that is sadly overlooked in the modern era of consensus-building and &amp;ldquo;collaborative working environments&amp;rdquo;. People are driven to excel when they feel they have something to prove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give the other person a fine reputation to live up to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Assume a virtue, if you have it not&amp;rdquo; - Shakespeare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People have an inherent desire to be respected and reputable. If you praise someone on a virtue or skill, they will work extra hard to attempt to maintain the opinion they think you have of them - even if they don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily possess these qualities in the first place!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, finally, a principle that underlies Carnegie&amp;rsquo;s entire book:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be genuinely interested in people&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the book, all of Carnegie&amp;rsquo;s principles reference back to this one, overarching theme - from &amp;ldquo;be sympathetic&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;allow the other person to save face&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;begin with praise and appreciation&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;call attention to mistakes indirectly&amp;rdquo;, each rule is based on a solid foundation of being aware of and concerned with the other person&amp;rsquo;s wellbeing, feelings, and reputation. Even perhaps the simplest and most obvious rule in the book, &amp;ldquo;smile&amp;rdquo;, is difficult if not impossible if one is unable to adhere to this principle in his dealings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How To Win Friends And Influence People&amp;rdquo; is a decent primer for improving your interpersonal skills in professional environments, and may find applicability in the political sphere in terms of finding benefactors or schmoozing political allies, but the techniques described are limited in the sense that they are unlikely to persuade or influence someone who is decidedly opposed to you in the first instance, and require concerted practice to master.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;choice-quotes&#34;&gt;Choice quotes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-16&#34;&gt;Page 16&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“For years I have kept an engagement book showing all the appointments I had during the day. My family never made any plans for me on Saturday night, for the family knew that I devoted a part of each Saturday evening to the illuminating process of self-examination and review and appraisal. After dinner I went off by myself, opened my engagement book, and thought over all the interviews, discussions and meetings that had taken place during the week. I asked myself: “‘What mistakes did I make that time?’ “‘What did I do that was right—and in what way could I have improved my performance?’ “‘What lessons can I learn from that experience?’ “I often found that this weekly review made me very unhappy. I was frequently astonished at my own blunders. Of course, as the years passed, these blunders became less frequent. Sometimes I was inclined to pat myself on the back a little after one of these sessions. This system of self-analysis, self-education, continued year after year, did more for me than any other one thing I have ever attempted. “It helped me improve my ability to make decisions—and it aided me enormously in all my contacts with people. I cannot recommend it too highly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-28&#34;&gt;Page 28&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When dealing with people, let us remember we are not dealing with creatures of logic. We are dealing with creatures of emotion, creatures bristling with prejudices and motivated by pride and vanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-122&#34;&gt;Page 122&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can be sure of being right only 55 percent of the time, you can go down to Wall Street and make a million dollars a day. If you can’t be sure of being right even 55 percent of the time, why should you tell other people they are wrong?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-123&#34;&gt;Page 123&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Lord Chesterfield said to his son: Be wiser than other people if you can; but do not tell them so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-124&#34;&gt;Page 124&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s magic, positive magic, in such phrases as: “I may be wrong. I frequently am. Let’s examine the facts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-153&#34;&gt;Page 153&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Socrates, “the gadfly of Athens,” was one of the greatest philosophers the world has ever known. He did something that only a handful of men in all history have been able to do: he sharply changed the whole course of human thought; and now, twenty-four centuries after his death, he is honored as one of the wisest persuaders who ever influenced this wrangling world. His method? Did he tell people they were wrong? Oh, no, not Socrates. He was far too adroit for that. His whole technique, now called the “Socratic method,” was based upon getting a “yes, yes” response. He asked questions with which his opponent would have to agree. He kept on winning one admission after another until he had an armful of yeses. He kept on asking questions until finally, almost without realizing it, his opponents found themselves embracing a conclusion they would have bitterly denied a few minutes previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-154&#34;&gt;Page 154&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chinese have a proverb pregnant with the age-old wisdom of the Orient: “He who treads softly goes far.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-162&#34;&gt;Page 162&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ralph Waldo Emerson in his essay “Self-Reliance” stated: “In every work of genius we recognize our own rejected thoughts; they come back to us with a certain alienated majesty.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-187&#34;&gt;Page 187&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“All men have fears, but the brave put down their fears and go forward, sometimes to death, but always to victory” was the motto of the King’s Guard in ancient Greece. What greater challenge can be offered than the opportunity to overcome those fears?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;page-223&#34;&gt;Page 223&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Childish? Perhaps. But that is what they said to Napoleon when he created the Legion of Honor and distributed 15,000 crosses to his soldiers and made eighteen of his generals “Marshals of France” and called his troops the “Grand Army.” Napoleon was criticized for giving “toys” to war-hardened veterans, and Napoleon replied, “Men are ruled by toys.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
